# Dominic Chalcraft

40 Dyke Road

Basement Flat

Mobile: 07393 507 018

Email: dmshelleytaylor@googlemail.com

East Sussex, BN1 3JB

Github: @domchalcraft O

#### Personal Statement

My developer experience so far has encompassed many aspects of website design, creation, hosting and maintenance which has allowed me to become a full stack engineer. For the last year I've been focused on back end development, with a heavy emphasis on API and CMS development, along with a large amount of sysadmin and devops. Ideally I would like to continue expanding my knowledge into new areas and improve upon the skills I have learned.

### Key Skills

Ruby MySQL, PostgreSQL API's and CMS's Rails, HAML, ERB NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis) TDD and BDD Fortran, C Git, Github Actions Ansible, Terraform

## **Experienced With**

Docker AWS (SQS, SES, S3, QS) Windows, OSX, Linux Javascript, React Rackspace, Krystal, Katapult Ubuntu Server Nginx, Passenger, Puma

## Recent Employment

#### Senior Developer [May 2022 to Present]

Audioboom PLC

At Audioboom I've mainly been a backend developer, sysadmin with a focus on Ubuntu systems, and a devops engineer. The tech stack is Rails (MySQL, Redis, Memcached) with React and I've worked in all parts. During my tenure I've tried to move the focus to a service oriented design in the hope of breaking out some parts of the codebase into their own applications. I've additionally set up new infrastructure to handle increasing demand. Some of the main acheivements while working there have been:

- Migrating all infrastructure (staging and production) from Ubuntu 18.04 to 22.04 with very little issue. Automated most of the process using Ansible.
- Migrated our Sphinx searching, which is now unmaintained, over to Manticore which involved setting up infrastructure to test, develop and deploy the new stack using Terraform.
- Migrated from Memcached to Redis for caching in rails. This involved setting up several caching servers, again using Terraform, in order to take the load from production. Some custom middleware was required due to restart issues on Redis and this became a core of redis-client in the form of a circuit breaker.
- Developed a tool for users to approve advertisers from the backend services to communicate with Salesforce API and data structures to the front end client facing CMS.

#### Backend Developer [May 2019 to May 2022]

Audioboom PLC

Some of the main acheivements while working as a backend developer were:

Dominic Chalcraft 2

- Migrating our email services from an old MX server over to Amazon SES, utilising SQS and setting up our own services for handling of bounces and complaints.

- Migrating our main servers from Solaris to Ubuntu
- Enforcing GDPR and PECR cookie policies across the site (including externally embeded videos)
- General bugfixing and strategic development to refactor and update code
- Created the backend code for the AdRip tool, a commercially successful product that allows users to increase revenue
- Set up a suite of virtual machines to manage web caching using Redis, moving away from Memcached
- Integrating external services into our systems so podcasts can be reliably and asynchronously distributed
- Added backend functionality that facilitates adverts to be targeted more effectively

## **Previous Employment**

#### Developer [Oct 2015 to May 2019]

Homeflow Ltd

As a mid level engineer my duties at Homeflow ranged from back end development of our customer facing applications to front end development of our websites as well day to day bug fixes and mentoring of junior developers. I aslo helped manage many of our server deploys in a sysadmin/devlops type role, overseeing the architectural improvements required for a rapidly growing business. I often had to design custom solutions to requested client development, taking customer specifications and creating software from the bottom up. Some of the projects I headed were:

- Building a CMS application, using Ruby on Rails, from the ground up. The CMS linked up to the MySQL database via a Rails API which I was heavily involved in creating and maintaining.
- Upgrade of our main API from Rails 4 to Rails 5 and Ruby 2.5 (from 2.1.3).
- Improving test coverage of the database to front-end API to improve security and facilitate code cleanups and upgrades of Ruby and Rails.
- An application that allows clients to graphically view their websites main metrics (users, sessions, bounce rates etc) as provided by Google analytics and our own internal data collection.
- Server maintenance (keeping things online when there's an outage), deployment scheduling, managing infrastructure upgrades and fixing servers that developers may have broken
- Mentoring junior and mid level developers to get to grips with the systems
- Being on call whenever the site was down or there was a server outage and rapidly fixing those issues

### Education

Physics, MPhil [2012-2013] *University of Bath, Claverton Down, BA2 7AY* 

Theoretical Physics, MPhys (First) [2007-2011] *University of Sussex, Falmer, Brighton, BN1 9RH* 

A-Levels [2003-2005]: Physics (A), Chemistry (A), Mathematics (A), Biology (A). City College Brighton and Hove, Pelham Street, Brighton, BN1 4FA

G.C.S.E.'s [2002-2003]: Double-Science  $(A^*A^*)$ , Mathematics (A), Astronomy (A), English (A). City College Brighton and Hove, Pelham Street, Brighton, BN1 4FA